They were divided by war. He united them in song.
The Choral is a comedy, drama, music film directed by Nicholas Hytner.
As World War I rages on, Dr.
Henry Guthrie takes over a British choral society
that's lost most of its men to the army.
The community soon discovers that the best response to the
chaos of war is to make beautiful music together.
Dr. Henry Guthrie, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Alderman Bernard Duxbury, played by Roger Allam.
Joe Fytton, played by Mark Addy.
Herbert Trickett, played by Alun Armstrong.
Robert Horner, played by Robert Emms.
Mrs. Bishop, played by Lyndsey Marshal.
The Choral is a 2025 British historical drama film co-produced and
directed by Nicholas Hytner and written by Alan Bennett.
Set in 1916, during World War I, in the fictional town of Ramsden, Yorkshire, the film follows the members of the local choral society which recruits a group
of teenage boys and girls for a performance of Edward Elgar's The Dream of Gerontius, a work chosen because it was not written by a German.
It stars Ralph Fiennes, Roger Allam, Mark Addy, Alun
Armstrong, Robert Emms, and Simon Russell Beale.
The film explores themes of world war i, choir,
yorkshire, period drama, frantic.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.